<item>
	<title>Ryanair is teasing Easyjet</title>
	<link>http://xdamman.posterous.com/ryanair-is-teasing-easyjet</link>
	<pubDate>Mon Jan 01 18:20:41 -0800 2007</pubDate>
	
	<dc:creator><![CDATA[Xavier Damman]]></dc:creator>
	
	

	<category><![CDATA[Uncategorized]]></category>

	<category domain="category" nicename="uncategorized"><![CDATA[Uncategorized]]></category>

  <guid isPermaLink="false">http://xdamman.posterous.com/ryanair-is-teasing-easyjet</guid>
	<description></description>
	<content:encoded><![CDATA[I've just taken a flight from Charleroi (Brussels) to Madrid with Ryanair.

<div class='p_embed p_image_embed'>
<img alt="Media_httpwwwxavierda_xiwhd" height="100" src="http://getfile4.posterous.com/getfile/files.posterous.com/import-cjvw/ionqxEziroblhqjGyJoqFwHlkktCbyxxvFutxyxtIkwDyswIoixJFAcJGsqD/media_httpwwwxavierda_xiwHD.jpg.scaled500.jpg" width="133" />
</div>


On the plane, it was written "Bye bye EasyJet" (as shown on this picture I took).
Does anybody has an another explanation than the fact the Ryanair is teasing his competitor EasyJet?

P.S: I tried to take in my hand back a belgian beer (a Bush special Xmas, 12°) just for fun, to check their brand new security rule, and, as expected, they didn't let me enter the plane with it.
Welcome to the 21th century where you are considered as a terrorist (or at least a dangerous person) with a beer in your bag.
Actually there is no need to have a beer, it also works with a bottle of water.
As I did in Heathrow (London) this September. They emptied my bottle of water and refill it after the security gate (because I was complaining 'cause I had to stay about 7 hours in that airport and I was not going to change money to buy a new bottle). Brillant.]]></content:encoded>
	<excerpt:encoded><![CDATA[I've just taken a flight from Charleroi (Brussels) to Madrid with Ryanair. On the plane, it was written "Bye bye EasyJet" (as shown on this picture I took). Does anybody has an another explanation than the fact the Ryanair is teasing his competito...]]></excerpt:encoded>	

	<wp:post_date>Mon Jan 01 18:20:41 -0800 2007</wp:post_date>
	<wp:post_date_gmt>Mon Jan 01 18:20:41 -0800 2007</wp:post_date_gmt>
	<wp:comment_status>open</wp:comment_status>
	<wp:ping_status>open</wp:ping_status>
	<wp:post_id>22760744</wp:post_id>
	<wp:post_name>ryanair-is-teasing-easyjet</wp:post_name>
	<wp:status>publish</wp:status>
	<wp:post_parent>0</wp:post_parent>
	<wp:menu_order>0</wp:menu_order>
	<wp:post_type>post</wp:post_type>
	<wp:post_password></wp:post_password>
	<wp:is_sticky>0</wp:is_sticky>

	
</item>
