<item>
	<title>Fuckin' security measures at Heathrow airport</title>
	<link>http://xdamman.posterous.com/fuckin-security-measures-at-heathrow-airport</link>
	<pubDate>Sat Feb 24 11:57:15 -0800 2007</pubDate>
	
	<dc:creator><![CDATA[Xavier Damman]]></dc:creator>
	
	

	<category><![CDATA[Uncategorized]]></category>

	<category domain="category" nicename="uncategorized"><![CDATA[Uncategorized]]></category>

  <guid isPermaLink="false">http://xdamman.posterous.com/fuckin-security-measures-at-heathrow-airport</guid>
	<description></description>
	<content:encoded><![CDATA[As you might imagine, this post is not going to be a charm. 
Thanks to the new EU law, I just missed my connection and I have to wait for the next flight to Madrid. Fortunately, I just have to wait one hour.
But what if there wasn't any place available in that one?

How long will people accept any law for some obscure security reasons just like sheep?
How many planes have blown up because a passenger had liquid in his hand luggage? 
How many planes have crashed because a passenger had hidden explosive in a white liquid in a baby milk mug?
But you can still take a plane with polium120 as long as you take less than 100ml. Which is more than enough to kill  hundreds of persons. 
Worst, I took the plane with 3 batteries within those two were defect and had a high risk of explosion!!!  (see my post about my 3 batteries to know more about those).

So don't tell me it is for security reasons all this shit in the european airports.
It's just a lobbying to put pressure on people and to let them know that the terrorist threat is always present and that to have to let our parlements vote laws that restrict even more and more our freedom.
And by the way, it's also a very good law to hide an increase in the airport taxes. Since now you have to pay 2 euros if you are just a bit thirsty.
Duty free should be very happy of this.

<div class='p_embed p_image_embed'>
<img alt="Media_httpwwwxavierda_kaydf" height="100" src="http://getfile0.posterous.com/getfile/files.posterous.com/import-cjvw/BGqFlfepaDgjamfgkzhBjqlAtlBkqrIrjdvkJlwuathIiHuzrIABHFozjDJu/media_httpwwwxavierda_kayDf.jpg.scaled500.jpg" width="75" />
</div>
 <div class='p_embed p_image_embed'>
<img alt="Media_httpwwwxavierda_fwify" height="100" src="http://getfile2.posterous.com/getfile/files.posterous.com/import-cjvw/gsxEDmqGyAyjxbIsbhwclbpsJthEhAlmCwjdfeAEClwmhbedjJepvakrihbJ/media_httpwwwxavierda_fwiFy.jpg.scaled500.jpg" width="75" />
</div>

<em>2£ for one Coca-Cola... thank you!</em>

I remember when that law was voted by the european parliament. I was in Madrid and I was terrified to see in the newspaper that in overall, people agreed. The main argument was "if it is for our security...". These people probably never entered an airport. 

I beg your courage to stand against such stupid laws that doesn't serve any democratic interest.
If you do not agree with me, watch out to avoid bringing any liquid if you want to jump in my car. Unless you show me the evidence it's more dangerous to have liquids in a plane than in a car. But I'm really not convinced.
(P.S: Don't worry, from now on I will always have bottles of water in my car for selling at 5 euros each, just in case you may be thirsty).
<p style="text-align: right; font-size: 10px;">Technorati Tags: <a href="http://www.technorati.com/tag/heathrow" rel="tag">heathrow</a>, <a href="http://www.technorati.com/tag/liquid" rel="tag">liquid</a>, <a href="http://www.technorati.com/tag/security" rel="tag">security</a>, <a href="http://www.technorati.com/tag/tedeco" rel="tag">tedeco</a></p>]]></content:encoded>
	<excerpt:encoded><![CDATA[As you might imagine, this post is not going to be a charm. Thanks to the new EU law, I just missed my connection and I have to wait for the next flight to Madrid. Fortunately, I just have to wait one hour. But what if there wasn't any place avail...]]></excerpt:encoded>	

	<wp:post_date>Sat Feb 24 11:57:15 -0800 2007</wp:post_date>
	<wp:post_date_gmt>Sat Feb 24 11:57:15 -0800 2007</wp:post_date_gmt>
	<wp:comment_status>open</wp:comment_status>
	<wp:ping_status>open</wp:ping_status>
	<wp:post_id>22760696</wp:post_id>
	<wp:post_name>fuckin-security-measures-at-heathrow-airport</wp:post_name>
	<wp:status>publish</wp:status>
	<wp:post_parent>0</wp:post_parent>
	<wp:menu_order>0</wp:menu_order>
	<wp:post_type>post</wp:post_type>
	<wp:post_password></wp:post_password>
	<wp:is_sticky>0</wp:is_sticky>

	
</item>
