<item>
	<title>The trip back home to Madrid</title>
	<link>http://xdamman.posterous.com/the-trip-back-home-to-madrid</link>
	<pubDate>Sat Feb 24 17:04:38 -0800 2007</pubDate>
	
	<dc:creator><![CDATA[Xavier Damman]]></dc:creator>
	
	

	<category><![CDATA[Uncategorized]]></category>

	<category domain="category" nicename="uncategorized"><![CDATA[Uncategorized]]></category>

  <guid isPermaLink="false">http://xdamman.posterous.com/the-trip-back-home-to-madrid</guid>
	<description></description>
	<content:encoded><![CDATA[The trip back home passed almost flawlessly... 
So we left Ngozi at 8 am this Friday (yesterday). I had to go for one last time to the university to say bye to all but Apollinaire didn't have the time for that short way around.
I was a bit angry with that since I thought it was a bit unflexible from Apollinaire's part, and second, I had promised to Bénédicte to see her at the university because she had to give some letters to post from Europe.
And moreover, I didn't say bye to the others... so it was a bit bitter to leave everybody this way.

<div class='p_embed p_image_embed'>
<img alt="Media_httpwwwxavierda_dmuvr" height="100" src="http://getfile2.posterous.com/getfile/files.posterous.com/import-cjvw/mgsgudEvyydGlzBerHBayDBrafsDIhbvEmpgGDbcIDklCyyfluFegFsdAiIs/media_httpwwwxavierda_Dmuvr.jpg.scaled500.jpg" width="75" />
</div>
 <div class='p_embed p_image_embed'>
<img alt="Media_httpwwwxavierda_ncqnd" height="100" src="http://getfile6.posterous.com/getfile/files.posterous.com/import-cjvw/JmluJdaJhppCiJesmCErdHoFIEahFaklfIIvlviseFopdEsjGzqApiqfHGuH/media_httpwwwxavierda_nCqnd.jpg.scaled500.jpg" width="133" />
</div>

<em>The beach of the Tanganyika lake, and the plane from Bujumbura</em>
<p style="text-align: right; font-size: 10px;">Technorati Tags: <a href="http://www.technorati.com/tag/burundi" rel="tag">burundi</a>, <a href="http://www.technorati.com/tag/ngozi" rel="tag">ngozi</a></p>
<p><!--more--></p>
Anyway. So we went down to Bujumbura in Apolinaire's new suzuki 4x4. A trip of more than 2 hours. 
In Bujumbura, it's definitely way more hot than in Ngozi. I was sweating! 
We had to go here and there for Apolinaire's business and then we ate at 1pm and then we went a few minutes on the beach of the lac Tanganyika.
A quite peaceful place. But I couldn't stay there for more. It was really hot.

After that I took the plane towards Addis Ababa (Ethiopia). The flight is like a bus. It makes a stop at Entebbe (Ouganda) during half hour. Just the time to fill the plane.
At Addis Ababa, I had to wait for 5 hours. Hopefully I was with french young journalist who had their flight at around midnight (mine was at 2am). So we had some Ethiopian beers which helped us to pass the time :-)

At 2 we entered the plane and flew for a 7h30 journey. We landed at 7am local time at Heathrow (London). And then I miss my plane and had to take the next one for Madrid (see my next post).]]></content:encoded>
	<excerpt:encoded><![CDATA[The trip back home passed almost flawlessly... So we left Ngozi at 8 am this Friday (yesterday). I had to go for one last time to the university to say bye to all but Apollinaire didn't have the time for that short way around. I was a bit angry wi...]]></excerpt:encoded>	

	<wp:post_date>Sat Feb 24 17:04:38 -0800 2007</wp:post_date>
	<wp:post_date_gmt>Sat Feb 24 17:04:38 -0800 2007</wp:post_date_gmt>
	<wp:comment_status>open</wp:comment_status>
	<wp:ping_status>open</wp:ping_status>
	<wp:post_id>22760688</wp:post_id>
	<wp:post_name>the-trip-back-home-to-madrid</wp:post_name>
	<wp:status>publish</wp:status>
	<wp:post_parent>0</wp:post_parent>
	<wp:menu_order>0</wp:menu_order>
	<wp:post_type>post</wp:post_type>
	<wp:post_password></wp:post_password>
	<wp:is_sticky>0</wp:is_sticky>

	
</item>
