<item>
	<title>The weekend: a whole concept</title>
	<link>http://xdamman.posterous.com/the-weekend-a-whole-concept</link>
	<pubDate>Sun Feb 11 22:54:02 -0800 2007</pubDate>
	
	<dc:creator><![CDATA[Xavier Damman]]></dc:creator>
	
	

	<category><![CDATA[Uncategorized]]></category>

	<category domain="category" nicename="uncategorized"><![CDATA[Uncategorized]]></category>

  <guid isPermaLink="false">http://xdamman.posterous.com/the-weekend-a-whole-concept</guid>
	<description></description>
	<content:encoded><![CDATA[Saturday night, we went out with Bénédicte, Julien and Elias. First we all took an Amstel at the Safari Club (they serve it in big bottles of 75cl). Tables under a roof, with a 30 inch television showing an episode of "Les feux de l'amour" (or alike). At 11:30pm, we moved to the local discotheque, called "au petit arrêt" (the little stop).

<div class='p_embed p_image_embed'>
<img alt="Media_httpwwwxavierda_fiahm" height="100" src="http://getfile5.posterous.com/getfile/files.posterous.com/import-cjvw/ybqqnphzhCnJtftHgGfioobfluFGHmAlFEJHuGprvxGIemEulzgoegAGmvCa/media_httpwwwxavierda_fIaHm.jpg.scaled500.jpg" width="133" />
</div>


<p><!--more--></p>
The entrance fee is 1500FBU per person (about 1,10€), and the music was really good. A mix of african songs and black american hits, with some classics. Really nice.
Africans really have the rhythm in their skin. Most of them really danced so well. It was amazing.
Besides, when they dance, they are really hot.

<div class='p_embed p_image_embed'>
<img alt="Media_httpwwwxavierda_mdbqg" height="100" src="http://getfile9.posterous.com/getfile/files.posterous.com/import-cjvw/JnzIyFbnooqirhGgvgugHeHFmewtcFrsIFjcyhcHrBxycdnHHdFdndHIrcft/media_httpwwwxavierda_mDBqG.jpg.scaled500.jpg" width="75" />
</div>

<em>Julien in an incredible dance
</em>
We danced till 3:30. When we went back, Bénédicte dropped me near my hotel, but when I arrived the main door was closed and the gate keeper wasn't awake. No way to climb it. So I went by foot to Julien and Bénédicte's house, 400m in complete darkness without any torch. Wow. Hopefully their gate keeper was awake and he let me enter. And I eventually slept in an empty room of their house. At 8:30am I had to wake up because one of my student had to give me back the key of the computer room. So we met and I went back to sleep but at the hotel this time.
At 11 Julien caught me to play soccer with the local team of veterans. They play very well and it was difficult for us to follow them, especially under the heavy sun of midday.
After that, they offered us 2 beers (remember that here, one beer is always 75cl) and a cool plate with a brochette and vegetables. It was in a really cool place with a so wonderful landscape. Unfortunately I didn't have my camera.

A bit drunk and burnt by the sun, we finally went back home to have some rest while the weather turned to an heavy rain (which caused electricity blackout).

We did a lot of things this weekend, and had very good time. I really enjoyed it.
Tomorrow, it's Monday and it's already time to go back to work as usual.]]></content:encoded>
	<excerpt:encoded><![CDATA[Saturday night, we went out with Bénédicte, Julien and Elias. First we all took an Amstel at the Safari Club (they serve it in big bottles of 75cl). Tables under a roof, with a 30 inch television showing an episode of "Les feux de l'amour" (or ali...]]></excerpt:encoded>	

	<wp:post_date>Sun Feb 11 22:54:02 -0800 2007</wp:post_date>
	<wp:post_date_gmt>Sun Feb 11 22:54:02 -0800 2007</wp:post_date_gmt>
	<wp:comment_status>open</wp:comment_status>
	<wp:ping_status>open</wp:ping_status>
	<wp:post_id>22760706</wp:post_id>
	<wp:post_name>the-weekend-a-whole-concept</wp:post_name>
	<wp:status>publish</wp:status>
	<wp:post_parent>0</wp:post_parent>
	<wp:menu_order>0</wp:menu_order>
	<wp:post_type>post</wp:post_type>
	<wp:post_password></wp:post_password>
	<wp:is_sticky>0</wp:is_sticky>

	
</item>
