<item>
	<title>Democracy 2.0 - Because we need a new system to cope with today's new challenges</title>
	<link>http://xdamman.posterous.com/democracy-20-because-we-need-a-new-system-to</link>
	<pubDate>Mon Mar 16 00:01:44 -0700 2009</pubDate>
	
	<dc:creator><![CDATA[Xavier Damman]]></dc:creator>
	
	

	<category><![CDATA[Uncategorized]]></category>

	<category domain="category" nicename="uncategorized"><![CDATA[Uncategorized]]></category>

  <guid isPermaLink="false">http://xdamman.posterous.com/democracy-20-because-we-need-a-new-system-to</guid>
	<description></description>
	<content:encoded><![CDATA["Democracy: a system of government by the whole population or all the eligible members of a state, typically through elected representatives"

Today we are facing challenges that are bigger than us: the climate crisis and the financial crisis. Our governments are mainly unable to cope with these new challenges. For the majority of them, they are stuck with short term decisions. They spend tax payers' money to save failed industries.
<strong>We need to rethink our democracies
</strong>

Our Occidental democracies are based on paper. Political parties are sending their program on paper. Citizens vote on paper. But paper is expensive. Paper takes time to be printed and more importantly paper are essentially a one-way communication channels.

As a result, citizens can only vote every 5 years or so. In the time in between, they have little interaction with their representatives. As our memories used to be short, they can basically do whatever except during the last 6 months before an election.
<div style="text-align: center;"><div class='p_embed p_image_embed'>
<a href="http://getfile0.posterous.com/getfile/files.posterous.com/import-cjvw/CwvgBInwohotxEtIIohIubeutoaFHkkwktevHCfdtIrzktrshHhfqwbCajbi/media_httpwwwxavierda_GHDcl.png.scaled1000.png"><img alt="Media_httpwwwxavierda_ghdcl" height="722" src="http://getfile3.posterous.com/getfile/files.posterous.com/import-cjvw/CwvgBInwohotxEtIIohIubeutoaFHkkwktevHCfdtIrzktrshHhfqwbCajbi/media_httpwwwxavierda_GHDcl.png.scaled500.png" width="500" /></a>
</div>
</div>
<div style="text-align: center;">In current democracies, there are almost no interaction with citizens and with expert. Collaboration is limited.</div>
<p />
<strong>Voting paper can't be personalized </strong>
On top of that, paper cannot be personalized. Every single citizen, whether he is a worker or a non-worker, a youngster or an old person, get the same paper. They all have to answer the same questions. They all have to vote for the same people. And as every human, these people are good for some subjects but can't be good for solving all the different issues we are facing as a society.

I would love that our governments ask us much more our thinking. But they can't do it on paper. It is too expensive and they would need to spend too much time to educate the whole population to make sure they can take a good decision (look at all the debates about the European Constitution in France!).

What I want is a clever democracy. I don't wanna be asked about what to do regarding agriculture policies (I'm not a farmer), I don't wanna be asked about what to do regarding education at this time (I'm not a teacher, I have no kids). But, I do wanna be asked about what to do to foster entrepreneurship, about what to do make our institutions more efficient. For the rest, I trust my fellow citizens who are more directly impacted or have time to dig into the subject.

You can't ask to everybody their thinking about everything. But this remains unthinkable in our current democracies.

<strong>It's not about left and right wing anymore, it's about communities</strong>

People used to gather behind this simple paradigm: you are whether a socialist (left wing) or a liberal (right wing). But this leads to useless competition and decisions based on the politic party you support instead of your real skills to fit the job as a leader.

This means that our leaders don't have to collaborate with the best people out there to make our society work better. They have to compete, they have to be winners and make the other lose next elections.
<div style="text-align: center;"><div class='p_embed p_image_embed'>
<a href="http://getfile7.posterous.com/getfile/files.posterous.com/import-cjvw/bysvqueqlorBEcBDfpxukhHEsJbiccHmGbcpHClvuAecgaBbdApekAqqCIqi/media_httpwwwxavierda_oaduv.png.scaled1000.png"><img alt="Media_httpwwwxavierda_oaduv" height="586" src="http://getfile3.posterous.com/getfile/files.posterous.com/import-cjvw/bysvqueqlorBEcBDfpxukhHEsJbiccHmGbcpHClvuAecgaBbdApekAqqCIqi/media_httpwwwxavierda_oaduv.png.scaled500.png" width="500" /></a>
</div>
</div>
<div style="text-align: center;">In a Democracy 2.0, Citizens could participate in chosen topics</div>
<p />
<span style="font-weight: bold;">From parliament members to community managers</span>
What we need is leaders that will collaborate with people expert in their field. We need leaders who won't pretend to be able to give answers to all subjects of our society. Tomorrow's new leaders need be closer of their communities. They need to foster the debates, be more transparent, in one word; they need to be "Community managers".
<div style="text-align: center;"><div class='p_embed p_image_embed'>
<a href="http://getfile4.posterous.com/getfile/files.posterous.com/import-cjvw/tJilkmkBzAherHqsynpqreEuxtgpAEqyjeiuuaqCxxEhlDrspqeGoAtvnHdI/media_httpwwwxavierda_yFDCf.png.scaled1000.png"><img alt="Media_httpwwwxavierda_yfdcf" height="536" src="http://getfile2.posterous.com/getfile/files.posterous.com/import-cjvw/tJilkmkBzAherHqsynpqreEuxtgpAEqyjeiuuaqCxxEhlDrspqeGoAtvnHdI/media_httpwwwxavierda_yFDCf.png.scaled500.png" width="500" /></a>
</div>
</div>
<div style="text-align: center;">In a Democracy 2.0, parliament members should ask as Community Managers</div>
<p />
<strong>Democracy 1.0 relies on paper, Democracy 2.0 will use the Internet as the new paper
</strong>

Today we have a new technology at hand: The Internet. For the first time in human history, we can put together a majority of citizens through a two-way communication channel. Why not using this to build a new paradigm of democracy?

It is cheap and it allows personalisation. Citizens would be able to choose in which subjects they are mostly interested. They will not be bothered with unfamiliar topics. But they will have a lot of things to say to things which would impact them directly.]]></content:encoded>
	<excerpt:encoded><![CDATA["Democracy: a system of government by the whole population or all the eligible members of a state, typically through elected representatives" Today we are facing challenges that are bigger than us: the climate crisis and the financial crisis. Our ...]]></excerpt:encoded>	

	<wp:post_date>Mon Mar 16 00:01:44 -0700 2009</wp:post_date>
	<wp:post_date_gmt>Mon Mar 16 00:01:44 -0700 2009</wp:post_date_gmt>
	<wp:comment_status>open</wp:comment_status>
	<wp:ping_status>open</wp:ping_status>
	<wp:post_id>22760652</wp:post_id>
	<wp:post_name>democracy-20-because-we-need-a-new-system-to</wp:post_name>
	<wp:status>publish</wp:status>
	<wp:post_parent>0</wp:post_parent>
	<wp:menu_order>0</wp:menu_order>
	<wp:post_type>post</wp:post_type>
	<wp:post_password></wp:post_password>
	<wp:is_sticky>0</wp:is_sticky>

	
		<wp:comment>
			<wp:comment_id>comment.id</wp:comment_id>
			
				<wp:comment_author><![CDATA[Pattaya Rag]]></wp:comment_author>
			
			<wp:comment_date>Sat Mar 12 06:05:52 -0800 2011</wp:comment_date>
			<wp:comment_date_gmt>Sat Mar 12 06:05:52 -0800 2011</wp:comment_date_gmt>
			<wp:comment_content><![CDATA[The rich and powerful are happy with the existing system as it is easy for them to ''influence'' elected officials to do their bidding. These groups just want a form of government that puts their needs before the needs of the voters. It's a form of government that we normally associate with third world countries but is in fact the current form of government in the U.S. and Britain.

Until this failing of modern democracies is addressed nothing else matters. 


   

]]></wp:comment_content>
			<wp:comment_approved>1</wp:comment_approved>
			<wp:comment_type></wp:comment_type>
			<wp:comment_parent>0</wp:comment_parent>
		</wp:comment>
	
</item>
