<item>
	<title>Black Monday</title>
	<link>http://xdamman.posterous.com/black-monday-6</link>
	<pubDate>Mon Feb 12 13:06:44 -0800 2007</pubDate>
	
	<dc:creator><![CDATA[Xavier Damman]]></dc:creator>
	
	

	<category><![CDATA[Uncategorized]]></category>

	<category domain="category" nicename="uncategorized"><![CDATA[Uncategorized]]></category>

  <guid isPermaLink="false">http://xdamman.posterous.com/black-monday-6</guid>
	<description></description>
	<content:encoded><![CDATA[Monday was a black day. My both classes had to pass a test, and I found to be quite bad at my job that day.
Explanations...

<p><!--more--></p>
As you all know, it's my very first experience as a teacher. Though I give class at the University, it's more comparable to a college class. Moreover, I've got only 12 to 14 student by class (about 7 hours a day).

So, it was also the very first time I had to make a test for my students.
I was happy with my questions. One of theory that could be found in the notes, one about demonstrating new properties about the algebra operations we have seen in class (so, they had to think since these properties were new for them), and one question of application.
The only problem is that they needed much more time that I thought. If I had to pass that test, I would have used about 15mn, however, they needed 1h30!
Poor students...

But at the end, the average of the class was 80% which really surprised me according to the questions I've asked. So I was very happy! It's really a great satisfaction to see that your previous week's hard work was not vain.

After the break, I gave class for one hour. And it was terrible. I didn't prepare during the weekend, and it was really crappy. Probably the student haven't noticed it, whatever, I know that I was very bad. While I was explaining I was saying to myself "damn, why do you start by this and not by this? Argh, too late, now they will be confused...".

The afternoon, test for my second class. They needed only half hour so it was really ok (too ok?).
But the results are not that good. The average of the class is only 62%. Ok it's Databases 2, which means that it is way more difficult but still...

After that, and exactly as in the morning, I was really bad at teaching. Pouah...

Anyway...

After the class, I stood at the university to correct the tests. At 7:30pm, the current failed. Total blackout. I had to use my gsm as a torch just to find my pen back! It was really scaring. Hopefully, there were students in another room that were leaving the university, and they went with me out on the street, then towards the main street till I could take a Bicycle taxi. All of this in the dark. So from now on, be sure that I will always have my electric torch in my backpack! :-)]]></content:encoded>
	<excerpt:encoded><![CDATA[Monday was a black day. My both classes had to pass a test, and I found to be quite bad at my job that day. Explanations... As you all know, it's my very first experience as a teacher. Though I give class at the University, it's more comparable to...]]></excerpt:encoded>	

	<wp:post_date>Mon Feb 12 13:06:44 -0800 2007</wp:post_date>
	<wp:post_date_gmt>Mon Feb 12 13:06:44 -0800 2007</wp:post_date_gmt>
	<wp:comment_status>open</wp:comment_status>
	<wp:ping_status>open</wp:ping_status>
	<wp:post_id>22760705</wp:post_id>
	<wp:post_name>black-monday</wp:post_name>
	<wp:status>publish</wp:status>
	<wp:post_parent>0</wp:post_parent>
	<wp:menu_order>0</wp:menu_order>
	<wp:post_type>post</wp:post_type>
	<wp:post_password></wp:post_password>
	<wp:is_sticky>0</wp:is_sticky>

	
</item>
