<item>
	<title>Fed up with SPAM, the empire strikes back</title>
	<link>http://xdamman.posterous.com/fed-up-with-spam-the-empire-strikes-back</link>
	<pubDate>Mon Jan 22 22:45:22 -0800 2007</pubDate>
	
	<dc:creator><![CDATA[Xavier Damman]]></dc:creator>
	
	

	<category><![CDATA[Uncategorized]]></category>

	<category domain="category" nicename="uncategorized"><![CDATA[Uncategorized]]></category>

  <guid isPermaLink="false">http://xdamman.posterous.com/fed-up-with-spam-the-empire-strikes-back</guid>
	<description></description>
	<content:encoded><![CDATA[We all have that fuckin' problem, a ton of spams in our mailbox.
Although the anti-spam filters are gettin' more and more accurate, there are always some spam passing through all these shields.

From now on, I decided to strike back. So every time I get an unsolicited mail, I answer by this:
"Vous avez 72h pour me prouver que je vous ai donné mon accord pour m'envoyer votre publicité.

Vivant actuellement à Madrid, la juridiction espagnole fera droit. Celle-ci prévoit une amende pouvant aller jusqu'à 600.000€ pour non respect de données de la vie privée d'un individu.
Mon avocat ayant déjà gagné plusieurs cas similaires, il sera ravi de gérer le vôtre.

Bien à vous,"

<p style="text-align: right; font-size: 10px;">Technorati Tags: <a href="http://www.technorati.com/tag/spam" rel="tag">spam</a>, <a href="http://www.technorati.com/tag/tribunal" rel="tag">tribunal</a></p>
<p><!--more--></p>
Which means:

"You have 72 hours to prove me that I gave you my authorization to send me your advertise.
Living at the moment in Madrid, the Spanish juridiction will be applied. This one allows me to ask as much as 600,000€ for non-respect of private data.
Knowing that my lawyer already won a couple of cases like this, I'm sure he will be glad to take yours in consideration.

Sincerely yours,"

I already sent it to sport-decouverte.com and here is their first answer:

<em>"Nous avons une base de mailling dans lequel nous mettons uniquement les internautes qui sollicitent à recevoir nos newsletters, à savoir les clients de Sport Découverte qui ont effectué une commande ou qui ont participé à notre Jeu concours de Noel. Nous ne pratiquons absolument pas de Spamming ce qui est contraire à notre déontologie !"</em>
"We have a database for mailings in which we put only the visitors that want to receive our newsletter, which means our clients that have already booked something or people that have participated in our Xmas competition. We don't do spamming which is contrary to our deontology".

After saying them that I've never been one of their clients, they told me this:

<em>"Je vous répète que Sport Découverte ne fait pas de Spamming !
Par contre, nous avons réalisé quelques envois de newsletter via des sociétés qui nous ont loué leur base sachant que les adresses sont opt-in.
J'espère que c'est effectivement le cas, parque dans le cas contraire, je m'engage à vous aider dans votre démarche."
</em>"I repeat that we do not spamming!
Nevertheless, we sent some newsletters through companies that have rented us their database knowing that theirs mails address where opt-in (ie: when you check the box "I allow that you give my data to third-parties", which of course, I've never done).
I hope it's really the case, if not, I commit myself to help you in your quest".

Really interesting since their speech has evolved! Now they admit they have used some third-party databases!

After that the guy told me that I was arrogant (yeah for sure, it was on purpose) and that if I wanted to go further, I had to contact his lawyer. So I let it as it is.

Is there any way to put these companies to the tribunal?
I understand it's not possible when you get spam from USA or from nowhere but when you get something from the country nextdoor, in your language, you should be able to do something no?
Especially when it comes from a "regular" company. I mean, a company that is not selling Viagra or porno, o fake-diploma.

If you know a way, let me know!
I would be very happy to put once someone to tribunal for that just to scare all the others by jurisprudence.]]></content:encoded>
	<excerpt:encoded><![CDATA[We all have that fuckin' problem, a ton of spams in our mailbox. Although the anti-spam filters are gettin' more and more accurate, there are always some spam passing through all these shields. From now on, I decided to strike back. So every time ...]]></excerpt:encoded>	

	<wp:post_date>Mon Jan 22 22:45:22 -0800 2007</wp:post_date>
	<wp:post_date_gmt>Mon Jan 22 22:45:22 -0800 2007</wp:post_date_gmt>
	<wp:comment_status>open</wp:comment_status>
	<wp:ping_status>open</wp:ping_status>
	<wp:post_id>22760725</wp:post_id>
	<wp:post_name>fed-up-with-spam-the-empire-strikes-back</wp:post_name>
	<wp:status>publish</wp:status>
	<wp:post_parent>0</wp:post_parent>
	<wp:menu_order>0</wp:menu_order>
	<wp:post_type>post</wp:post_type>
	<wp:post_password></wp:post_password>
	<wp:is_sticky>0</wp:is_sticky>

	
</item>
